他們說她知道 她的確知道她知道所有的事
They say she knew. She really knew. She knew the whole story.
在八十年代初她成為時裝界的傳奇
本片是根據認識她的人對她的描述
和她自己寫的日記拍攝而成
主演：安吉麗娜朱莉
片名：吉婭
那時 每個模特都長得比較高 比較瘦 都是金發碧眼的可人兒
At that time, everybody was tall, thin and blonde.
她們都會擺出一個姿勢 朝著你看
Everybody posed, everybody gave you a look.
但吉婭不同
But Gia was different.
她是第一個能做不斷地擺出各種姿勢
She was the first one who... Who moved.
現在的模特都會這樣做讓你能夠 選出一個最好的 但她是第一個
They all try to do it now, give you an attitude, but she invented it.
她總是隨心所欲...
She always followed her instincts
不管在哪里
no matter where they took her.
這也許她最好的一面但也許也 正是最糟糕的一面
It was probably the best and the worst thing about her.
說到吉婭總離不開性
with Gia, it was always about the sex.
每一個眼神 每一個動作 每一分鐘 每一天
Every look, every move, every minute. Every day.
都離不開性
Sex.
他們妒忌她現在也是 那就是為什么他們總愛談論這個
They were jealous of her. They still are. That's why they say those things.
她的確與很多人睡過但這并不意昧著什么
She would come on to everybody, but it was really innocent.
我是說 并沒有人真正因這些被冒犯了
I mean, nobody was ever really offended by it.
我不認為這一切與性有關
I don't think it had anything to do with sex.
她不是為了性才與人上床的性不是目的
Even when she was sleeping around, sex was not the goal.
性真的不是問題
Sex wasn't really an issue.
是 我知道關于吸毒的事
Yeah, I knew about the drugs.
對于吸毒的人 我總是很擔心
I was afraid of the drugs, the way people used them.
一切發生得那么快
It all just happened so fast.
一切都來得那么突然到處都 可以看到她的照片
You know, all of a sudden, her face was just everywhere.
每個模特都會有那么一瞬間一我指的是 造出那精彩一剎那的人
Every model has a moment. I mean, the ones who make it at all.
在那一瞬間 那人的一切都成為了時尚
And being of the moment is everything in fashion.
時尚不是藝朮時尚也談不上是文化
Fashion is not art, you know. Fashion isn't even culture.
時尚只是廣告...
Fashion is advertising,
而廣告就意昧著錢
and advertising is money.
你花出的每一塊錢都會有所回報
And for every dollar you earn, someone has to pay.
很久很久以前很久很久以前
Once upon a time, once upon a time.
有一個神話
It was a fairy tale.
這個神話后來變成了現實
It was. It was a fairy tale come true.
我有兩個兒子 你知道他兒子總會離開你
I had two boys, you know, but boys you lose.
他們走了 與別的女人結婚了他們離開你了
They go away, they marry other women. They're gone.
而女兒會一直留在你身邊
A girl, you have forever.
當吉婭出生時我說：
When Gia was born, I said, "This one is mine."
- 看看 - 她是我的
- Look at you. - "All mine."
看看我
Look at me.
看看我們倆
Look at us.
我們多么漂亮啊
Look how pretty we are.
我是不是一我是不是最漂亮的?是的
Do I be? Do I be the prettiest, prettiest girl?
你是最漂亮的 是的
You do. You do be the prettiest. You do be that.
- 你到底是上哪里去了? - 外面
- Where the hell have you been? - Out.
- 外面?外面?外面哪兒? - 外面
- Out? Out? Out where? - Out.
哦 喬伊 別這樣
Joe, don't start.
別對我說 “別這樣”外面哪兒?告訴我你上哪兒去了
Don't tell me, "Don't start." Out where? Tell me where you've been.
- 喬伊 小聲點 - 別叫我小聲點
- Joe, lower your voice. - Don't tell me to lower my voice.
孩子們要知道你今晚上哪里去了
The kids know you haven't been home all night.
- 住口 - 告訴他們你上哪兒去了
- Cut it out! - Tell them where you've been.
今晚我沒心情說
I'm not in the mood for this tonight, Joe.
沒心情 嗯 ?
Not in the mood, huh?
- 離我遠點 - 誰和你在一起 凱西里恩 ?
- Just leave me alone. - Who were you with, Kathleen?
這不關你的事
It's none of your business.
別這樣對我說話 你這個裱子
Don't tell me it's none of my business you fucking whore.
- 滾出廚房 - 讓我看看 他是不是干過你了
- Get out. Get out of the kitchen. - Let me see. Did he fuck you?
- 住手 - 他干過你沒有?
- Stop! - Let me see. Did he fuck you?
- 哪里?讓我也感受一下 - 豬！把你的手拿開！
- Where? Let me feel! - Pig ! Get your hands off!
- 除了我還有誰干過那個地方? - 把你的手拿開！變態佬
- Who else has been in there besides me? - Get your hands off of me, jerk.
- 還有誰?嗯? - 你知道你令我想做什么嗎?
- Who else, huh? - You know how you make me feel?
- 你讓我想去死 你知道嗎? - 你想死?不！
- You make me wanna die. You know that? - You wanna die? No!
你不能死 除非是我要你死
You don't die until I tell you you can die.
你才能死 明白嗎?
That's when you die, God damn it, you hear me?
我要你死你才能死！
That's when you die!
把這個也放到后車箱里這個我拿著
Here, take this and put it in the car. I'll keep this one.
很久很久以前...
Once upon a time
在一個很遠很遠的王國...
in a kingdom far, far away
那兒住著一個小女孩...
there lived a young girl
有著一頭金發
whose hair was made of gold.
那個村里的人看到她 他們會說...
when the people in the village saw her,
“哦 她多美啊”
they said, "How beautiful she is."
一份牛排干酪 一份肉丸 一份意大利腸 加波蘿伏洛干酪
All Right, one cheesesteak, one meatball, one salami- provoIone.
在這里盯著 我到4:00回來
Keep your eye on the shop, I'll be back by 4:00.
就別把這里給燒了
Try not to burn the place down huh?
- 吉婭 你負責這里的一切 - 沒問題
- Gia, you're in charge. - All Right, boss.
嘿 拿好了走開 別擋道
Hey, get the food, get the food. Go, come on, come on, get outta here.
- 把錢收好了 你干什么? - 現在我負責
- Get the cash register. What are you doing? - I'm in charge!
- 嘿 - 你叫吉婭?
- Hey. - Is your name Gia?
對
Yeah.
- 有火嗎? - 別搞亂了
- Got a llght? - Stop screwing around.
我在附近見過你几次...
I've seen you a few times around the neighborhood and...
并且一你很緊張嗎?
Are you nervous?
是的
Yeah.
我令你感到緊張了?
Am I making you nervous?
是的
Yeah.
噢 那不錯這正是我想要的
Well, good, 'cause that's the idea.
- 你說什么? - 你嚇到了周圍的人...
- What's that? - You scare the shit out of people
而他們通常并不知道你有多可怕
and then they don't see how scared you are.
你有多可怕?
Are you scared?
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
T.J.湯姆但人們通常叫我T.J
T.J. Tom Junior, but T.J. is what they call me.
T.J. 和吉婭
T.J. and Gia.
我喜歡 跟我來
I like that. Come on.
- 我走了等一下 - 你上哪兒去?
- I'm leaving. - Hey, Gia, wait a minute. Where you going?
- 現在我說了算 我要走了 - 吉婭
- I'm in charge, and I'm leaving. - Gia.
- 這是比亞斯的嗎? - 他們太棒了
- Is that The Byrds? - They're so cool.
喔 我太喜歡了
Wow. Rock my world.
75美分?
Seventy- five cents?
好漂亮 漂亮 太漂亮了
It's pretty. Pretty. Very pretty.
你好 小姐
Hello, ladies.
這個能給我嗎?來
Can I have this? Come on.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
紋身?
- Tattoo? - Tattoos.
- 是給你紋身 - 你現在要紋身?
- Tattoo you. - You getting a tattoo now?
不 給你紋身
No, tattoo you.
我不會去紋身的 來吧 什么?
- I'm not getting a tattoo. - Come on. What? What?
看看那頭發太怪了
Look at that hair. It's fabulous.
你現在想紋身了嗎?
You want a tattoo now?
她一定很會玩
She'd be a Iot of fun.
你們在看誰?他還是我?
So who are you looking at, him or me?
哦 我不想談論性
I can't talk about the sex.
我是說 我怎么會知道
I mean, how would I know?
如果你一定要問那她從未與任何人 有過真正的性關系
If you ask me, she never really had sex with anybody.
不過她的確很喜歡拍照...
But she did love to be photographed,
人們也樂于為她拍照為她做些什么
and people loved to take pictures of her and do little things for her.
她不喜歡被人拍照
She hated being photographed.
你必須追著她把她綁住了才行
You had to run after her and tie her down.
你得幫他解開衣服拿掉頭發上的東西
Then you had to get past the clothes and the stuff in her hair.
但她很不一般
But she was special.
走吧
Kathleen, Let's go.
來了 來了
Coming, coming.
好了 我們走吧
All Right, Let's go.
他們讓她看了一幢漂亮的房子... 在火星上的
And they showed her a beautiful house on the planet Mars.
然后對她說“永遠住在這里吧”
And they said, "Come and live here forever."
那個小女孩說...
And the young girl said,
"哦 在火星上生活真是不一樣啊
"Mars is a planet where life's different.
安全 干淨 美好 ' '
"Safe, clean and pretty." Yes.
但一但怎么才能到那里呢?
But... But how do you get there?
坐計程車嗎?還是坐哪輛公車?
where do you find a taxi? which bus do you take?
好 就算你到了那里你又怎么 知道你已經到了?
Right? And how do you know you're there when you're there?
費城不適合她
Philadelphia was not ready for this,
但紐約不一樣
but New York was.
就是那一刻...
It was the Right moment,
那一刻一切成為了時尚
and being of the moment is everything in fashion.
當然你越是時尚...
But of course, the more you were of the moment,
你也就會越快過時
the faster you become of the past.
好吧 就從這里開始
Okay, Let's get this over with.
只要走進去盡要表現得友好些
Just go in there and try to be nice.
- 友好? - 是的
- Nice? - Yeah.
友好
Nice.
誰知道他們也許會喜歡上你
Who knows? Maybe they'll like you.
你是個很討人喜歡的女孩子去你的
- You are a very likable girl. - Fuck you.
好吧
Okay.
嗨
Hi.
我想見威廉敏娜庫伯
I'm here to see Wilhelmina Cooper.
你得等等 等會兒吧 寶貝
So's the rest of the world and the rest of the world's way ahead of you, honey.
找個座位坐吧
Take a seat.
我是約好的
I have an appointment.
請別挂
Hold, please.
好 你說吧
Of course you do.
11:00 吉婭 瑪瑞卡 蘭芝
11 :00, Gia Marle Carangi.
什么?
"G" what?
好
Okay.
是GIA
G- I- A.
看著GIA 你他媽的記住了 叫我吉婭
There. Gia. Just fuck the rest of it. Call me Gia.
能記住嗎寶貝?
Do you think you can remember that, honey?
是嗎?很好現在告訴那條母狗我在這里
Yeah? cool. Now tell the bitch I'm here.
我已經看過照片了 親愛的莫里斯寄給我了
I've already seen the pictures, darling.Morris  sent them.
我想見見真人
I wanted to see the real thing.
好啊 我現在就在這里
Well, this is it.
的確
It certainly is.
你把我的接待員嚇壞了
You practically gave my receptionist a coronary.
是的 好吧 你看 我到紐約來...
Yeah, well, look. This was a free trlp to New York,
如果我知道你要找的是他媽的賤貨瑪瑞什么的...
and if I knew you were looking for Marcla- fucking- Brady,
我寧愿呆在家里
I would've stayed home.
你怎么知道我要的是什么樣的人?
How do you know what I'm looking for?
看著我......我是在看 正在看
- Well, fuck, look at me. - I'm looking, I'm looking.
你知道 穿得象個飛女...
You know, dressing like a motorcycle tramp
可能會讓一個17歲的女孩看起來很有意思
is somewhat interesting for a 17-year-old girl.
但說話也這樣就不好了
Talking like one is not.
事實上 做模特不用說話...
In fact, talking at all is not really requlred in this professlon
甚至不希望她們說話
or even encouraged.
你不用對著相機 畫面說什么
Anything you might have to say you say through the camera, the image,
渴望成名就行了
and hopefully the product.
你所說的都是無關緊要的
What comes out of your mouth is totally irrelevant.
明白嗎?
Understood?
是的
Yes, sir.
這里是一份事業
Now, this is a career,
這是未來
this is a future,
是一種生活...
this is a life
如果你要的話
if you want it.
你是不是說你能給我一份工作?
Does that mean you can get me a job?
不
No.
不 我只是接見了你
I get you the interviews,
你得自己找到工作
you get the job.
我相信你能行
And I belive you will.
親愛的 這就是我的生活
Dear Diary, this is my life.
拜訪楊和羅賓卡姆 9:45
Go see Young & Rubicam, 9:45.
到露華濃拜訪某人 11:15
Go see people at Revlon, 11 :1 5.
拜訪吉米摩爾 鮑勃斯通 著名的Malowinksi...
Go see Jimmy Moore, Bob Stone, somebody "Malowinksl,"
然后...”不行 寶貝 你不是我們要找的‘'
and "Get lost, honey. You ain't what we're lookin' for."
- 下一個 - 謝謝 你媽的 再見
- Next! - Thank you and fuck you. Bye- bye.
是的 我不斷地拜訪可沒有人看我一眼
Yeah, I go see, I go see. Nobody sees me.
“啊 小事一件 到這邊來 轉過去讓我瞧瞧你后面”
"Piece of meat, come here. Show me your bag."
然后他們把手指插入你體內
And they stick their finger in you.
”我只是想測測你的體溫 "
"I just wanna taste your temperature."
拜訪 拜訪 拜訪 不斷地拜訪
Go see, go see, go see, go see somebody else.
我不適合這個 這根本就不適合我
I ain't no good at this. I ain't no good at this at all.
但即使你適合你真的能行嗎?
But even if you are good at it, what exactly are you good at?
- 你不可以走 - 我必須走了
- You can't leave now. - I have to go.
什么?什么?去費城?
What, what? To Philadelphia?
- 去做什么? - 我有事
- For what? - I got stuff.
我必須走
I have to go.
我得有人照顧才行我還只是個孩子
Well, somebody has to take care of me. I'm just a kid.
去你的
Bullshit.
費城有什么?有比我更重要的嗎?
What's in Philadelphia that's more important than me?
- 別那樣 - 別怎么樣?
- Do not do that. - Do not do what?
別假裝你要去做什么而你實際上并不想去做
Do not pretend you're gonna do something when you know you're not.
我想做什么了?
What am I not gonna do?
還有什么?
What else?
怎么了?
What?
- 知道我想要做什么嗎? - 什么?
- Do you know what I want? - What?
什么?
What?
合適嗎?
How do they fit?
到你了?
This turn you on?
對
Yeah.
- 還好 - 好了
- Kind of. - All Right.
到這邊來
Come here.
- 你以前和別的男人做過嗎? - 是的
- Have you ever had sex with a man? - Yeah.
有一次
Once.
還有呢?
And?
還有?我甚至和德國牧羊犬干過
And I could've done that with a German shepherd.
親愛的布克 這是生活的又一天
Dear Book, this is another day in the life.
生活就象一本書書就象是一只盒子
A life is like a book. A book is like a box.
一個盒子有六個面還有里面和外面
A box has slx sides, inside and outside.
你怎么能知道里面有什么?
So how do you get to what's inside?
你怎么能把里面的東西拿出來?
How do you get what's inside out?
很久很久以前有一個非常漂亮的女孩...
Once upon a time, there was a very pretty girl
住在一只美麗的盒子里大家都很喜歡她
who lived in a beautiful box and everybody loved her.
- 喂? - 喂?
- Yes, hello? - Hello?
- 什么? - 是誰啊?
- What? - Hello. Hi.
那是什么東西?
Who the hell is that?
- 威爾? - 那是誰?
- Will? - who is it?
- 他媽的 - 我睡不著
- Christ's sake. - I couldn't sleep.
吉婭
Gia.
- 現在是半夜啊 - 很晚了
- MiddIe of the night. - It's very late.
- 我知道 - 我靠
- l know. - God damn it.
那個是你丈夫?
Is that your husband?
- 是的 - 他不高興了?
- Yes. - ls he pissed?
是
Yes.
他酗酒?大家都這么說
Is it true that he drinks? I mean, that's what everybody says.
- 吉婭 - 他有暴力傾向?
- Gia. - And he gets violent?
你想要干嘛吉婭 ?
What is it you want, Gia?
如果他敢打你我會他媽的殺了他
If he ever lays a hand on you, I'll fucking kllI him.
你為什么睡不著?
Why can't you sleep?
我要我過來嗎?
Do you want me to come over?
你對明天感到很不安?
You're nervous about tomorrow.
是的
Yeah, I am.
每個人在面臨新事物的時候都會不安 你會沒事的
Well, everyone is nervous on their first shoot. You'll be fine.
是的 我只是不知道該做什么 你知道嗎?
Yeah, I just don't know what to do. You know?
吃過沒有?
Did you do your coIonic?
吃過了
Yeah.
很好
Good.
那就上床去吃一片半...耐波他 黃的和黑的
Go to bed now. Take one half of the NembutaI. The yellow and black.
你會沒事的
You'll be fine.
- 就象平時一樣 - 好的
- Just be yourself. - Okay, yeah.
那是指什么?
what is that?
哦 親愛的...
Darling,
如果我能為你或是為我自己回答的話...
if I could answer that for you or for me,
嗯 要生活在這個世界不是件容易的事
well, life on this planet would be a very different proposltion.
所以我對她說 '’瞧...我認識加爾文...
So I tell her, "Look, I know CaIvin and I asked him about you,
我問了他關于你的事...而他不知道你是誰 ' '
"and he didn't even know who you were."
- 她撒謊 - 哦 別這樣
- She's such a Lying slag. Did she fllp? - Oh, man.
能幫你些什么嗎?
Excuse me, can I heIp you?
是 是的能不能給我點咖啡?
Yeah, yeah. Could I have some more coffee, please?
- 你是吉婭? - 是的
- Are you Gia? - That's me.
你遲到了去洗個臉
You're late. Go wash your face.
我已經洗過了很高興見到你
I already did. It's nice to meet you, too.
要我幫你洗嗎?
What the hell am I gonna do with you?
讓我來
I got it.
我不知道我只是個從費城來的小姑娘
I don't know. I'm just some dumb girl from PhllLy.
天啊 她是頭野獸
Oh, my God, she's a beast.
她讓我感到害怕
She scares me.
她有沒有令你想到你母親?
Why, Phllllpe, does she remind you of your mother?
沒有 倒是讓我想起了我兄弟 謝天謝地 他現在在牢里
No, she reminds me of my brother. He's in jall now, thank Jesus.
好
Okay.
什么?
What?
不錯
It's wonderful.
讓我們來看看這張臉
Let's see this face.
我在看你是否要去拔黑頭粉刺
I'm checking to see if you need to be tweezed.
- 我已經拔過了 - 我是琳達
- I'm tweezed. - I'm Linda.
很高興見到你
Nice to meet you.
丑
Dreadful.
真丑
AbsoIuteLy horrendous.
露多點牙出來
More teeth.
每一張照片都是一個承諾不用守的承諾
Every photograph makes a promise, and the promise is never kept.
看智力損害
Look brain damaged.
這就是照片的偉大之所在
That's what makes a photo great.
而如果那個承諾是性...
And if the promise is sex,
- 而你又從中得到了什么 - 好
- then you really have something. - Good.
很好
Wonderful.
好了...
Well,
真是一堆狗屎
that was all shit.
- 去你媽的 - 去拿錢吧
- Fuck you. - Now we can pay our rent.
誰愿意留下來創造點藝朮的
Who wants to stay and make some art?
什么樣的藝朮?
What's art?
留在圍欄后面把衣服脫光
Keep the fence, lose the clothes.
不 謝謝 我要走了
No, thanks, I'm gone.
我走了再見
I'm outta here. See you.
如果琳達留下的話我就留下
I'll stay if Linda stays.
- 琳達? - 什么事?
- Linda, Liebling? - Yeah.
到圍欄那邊去
Go stand by the fence.
- 你想把我也拍到照片里去? - 是 是 是
- You want me in the shot? - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
你也把衣服脫了
And lose the clothes.
性一性真的很簡單
Sex... Sex was really easy. It was...
到處都是性但性又并不是真的很多
Sex was everywhere. It didn't really mean too much.
愛這樣東西是很難找的
Love... Love was the hard thing to find.
太多人并不佣有愛 即使你找到了
Even if you were looking for it, which not too many people were.
即使它就是你面前
Even if you found it, which not too many people did.
你又怎能保証這就是你想要的?
Even if it was Right there in front of you
你如何讓性一直存在呢?
how could you see it with all the sex in the way?
嘿 你上哪兒去?
Hey, where you going?
吉婭
Gia.
發生什么事了?怎么了?
What happened? What's the matter?
你怎么沒穿衣服
You don't have any clothes on.
說正題吧
Don't change the subject.
我有男朋友
I have a boyfriend.
那又怎么樣?
So?
我要走了
So, I have to go.
我要走了 我要走了 所有的人都要走
"I have to go, I have to go." Everybody has to go.
大家都他媽的要去哪里?
Where the fuck does everybody go when they have to go, huh?
你...你和我有...
You... You and I had a...
我是說 是說...我有...
I mean, it was... I had a...
我不知道
I don't know.
我是真心的
I'm really very square.
我也是
So am I.
是的 我看得出
Yeah, I can see that.
求你別走
Please, don't go.
別離開我 我會為你做早飯
Please, don't go. Please, I'll make you breakfast.
別這樣
Come on.
- 下樓嗎? - 不
- Going down? - No.
- 是的 - 不！
- Yes. - No!
不不 你在干什么啊?不
No, no. What are you doing? No.
- 很抱歉 - 琳達
- I'm so sorry. - Linda!
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我會打電話給你
I'll call you.
不是
Not.
就象一只小狗
It was like a puppy.
愛我 愛我 愛我
It was like, "Love me, Love me, Love me, Love me."
是的
I did.
是的 我走了
I did. I did Right away.
非凡的...
Extraordinary, as in phenomenal,
好象是在金礦中...
as in a gold mine.
凶惡的 脆弱的 老的 年輕的...
Tough, vulnerable, old, young,
頹廢的 純潔的...
decadent, innocent,
男人 女人
male, female.
你看上去真不錯
And you look like you don't give a shit.
我遇到了一個人一個我喜歡的人
I met somebody, someone I really like.
很好啊
Good. Good for you.
深吸一口氣 親愛的
Take a deep breath, darling.
你正在駕馭你的生活
You are in for the ride of your life.
保羅
Paolo.
把這該死的欄杆放下
Lower the fucking drawbrldge, Tony.
給我几張入場券
Give me some of those goddamn drink tickets.
你總是那么光彩照人斯戴普 這位一定就是吉婭了
Always a pIeasure to see you, too, Stephie, and this must be Gia.
你怎么知道我的名字?
How do you know my name?
我是神 我什么都知道
I'm God, I know everything.
你看?人人都知道你的名字
You see? Even God knows your name.
長著這么一張漂亮的臉蛋她根本不需要名字
With a face like that, she doesn't need a name.
事實上 托尼 我的臉的確長得不錯
Actually, Tony, my face is a little higher.
任何時間吉婭 任何時間都歡迎你
Anytime, Gia, anytime.
別小氣了 托尼
Stop being stingy, Tony.
這兒什么都有有鎮定劑 有香檳
That's Ollvier Chandon, as in champagne.
他很有錢 有一次我和他在車里做愛
Very rich. Did him in a car once.
我不記得當時車開得有多快了
I can't remember exactLy how fast we were going.
那是斯坦吉拉迪 常與徹麗爾干那事 他真的很能“干’'
That's Stan Girardi. Used to do it with Cheryl, but he's doable.
喬伊詹姆遜 很英俊 可惜是個同性戀
Joe Jamison. Beautiful, but gay.
但那沒關系
Not that that ever stopped me.
只要添添他的屁股
A little tongue up his ass,
他就是你的了
and he's all yours.
你踩到屎了 不是嗎?
You're full of shit, aren't you?
有時我也不相信 可這好象是事實
Look, sometimes even I don't belive it, but it's all true.
好了 別玩了
Okay, break it up.
- 到我這邊來 - 那人是誰?
- On your left. - Who was that?
不知道
I have no idea.
我是最美最美的姑娘
I do be the prettiest, prettiest girl. I do be that.
不 她是個新人 絕對的新人你有必要見一下她 你會喜歡上她的
No, she's new, brand new. You have to see her. You'll like her.
- 她已經上雜志封面了吉婭 - 對
- She's on the cover. - Gia, yeah.
沒有姓就叫吉婭
No last name. Just Gia.
不行
Boring.
Played out.
太肥
Fat.
不行
Boring.
太沒生氣了
Too dumb.
冬天里我們要肉
For winter, we need meat.
我們要的是臉上有血色的 不是防晒霜也不是礦泉水
We need someone with bloodin her veins. Not just suntan oll and mineraI water.
天啊 她的臉讓我惡心
Oh, God, I am so sick of her face.
- 這是誰? - 威廉敏娜的新人吉婭
- Who's this? - This is one of Wilhelmina's new girls, Gia.
這就是我們要的所謂的肉
This is meat.
這才是上等的牛肉她充滿了活力
This is sirloin. It's lusty.
我們要的就是這樣的充滿野性的
Winter is carnivorous. rich browns, reds, big animal prints.
就是她了 對
This is it. Yes!
嘿
Hey.
我剛買的 你覺得怎么樣?
I just bought it. What do you think?
- 哇 - “哇”?
- Wow. - "Wow"?
想出去兜一圈嗎?
Wanna go for a ride?
- 不知道 - 是啦 你想的 來吧
- I don't know. - Yeah, you do. Come on.
好極了!
Yes!
- 我們去哪里? - 費城
- Where we going? - Philadelphia.
什么?
What?
- 抓緊了 - 知道
- Hold on ! - I am !
你們是?
Yeah?
你好 凱西里恩
Hi, Kathleen.
吉婭 天啊
Gia. Oh, my God.
天哪快進來
Oh, my God ! Come on in.
- 快進來 - 這是我的女朋友 琳達
- Come on. - This is my girlfriend, Linda.
琳達 ? 耶 嗨 天啊 天啊
Linda? Yeah, hi. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
跟我說說紐約的事
So, tell me about New York.
天啊 就象是見到了多年不見的老友
Oh, God, it was like seeing an old girlfriend.
哦 是的 她告訴了我所有模特不為人知的事
Yeah, she told me all the gosslp about all the models.
比如誰的皮膚不好 誰的頭發不好她還告訴我她們的所做所為
You know, who had bad skin and who had bad hair.
還有她們都去些什么地方天啊
The things that they did, she told me about, the places that they went. Oh, my God.
天啊
Oh, my God !
你上了時尚雜志的封面了真讓人不敢相信
You're on the cover of Vogue! I can't belive it.
天啊 真漂亮不是嗎?
Oh, my God, isn't that beautiful?
寶貝
Oh, honey.
后來怎么樣了?有男朋友了嗎?
So what else is going on, huh? Do you have a boyfriend?
沒有琳達有
No. Linda has a boyfriend.
- 是嗎? - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
哦 是嗎?嗯 那很不錯
Well, that's nice.
- 我有一個女朋友 - 這也很不錯...
- I have a girlfriend. - Yeah, that's nice, too,
這不是一回事 不是嗎?
though it's not the same thing, is it?
我們從不談論過去的事一切都過去了
And we never talked about the past. That was over.
過去就是過去她從未和我談論過過去的事
The past was the past. She never discussed it with me once.
就好象一切都沒發生過
It was like it never happened, all those years in between.
It was like it never happened.
所有你寄給我的東西
I kept everything you've sent me.
我都保留著甚至是從你小的時候開始你摸過的
I keep everything you ever touched ever since you were a baby.
看看我有些什么對了 對了
What do I have? Oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
我的日記！
My journaI.
“很久很久以前...”
"Once upon a time..."
“很久很久以前 有一個金發的小女孩...”
"Once upon a time, there was a girl with golden hair
“住在一間漂亮的房子里”
"who went to llve in a beautiful house."
總是同一個故事
Always the same story, yeah?
又不一樣又一樣
Always different, always the same.
又一樣
Always the same.
我可以看嗎?
Can I see?
當然
Yeah.
有時我認為她是個與眾不同的姑娘
Sometimes I think she was a different person to everybody.
有時我很了解她
Sometimes I knew who she was.
有時卻不
Sometimes I didn't.
如果有誰說知道她的一切...
Anybody who trles to tell you exactLy who she was,
那個人其實根本不了解她
they didn't know her at all.
在那些日子里我們不論做什么都在一起
We did everything together. Yeah, in those days.
對 所有一切
Yeah, everything.
好吧
All right.
這是...
This is...
我能說什么呢?
What can I say? It's you.
這個公寓是我隨便找來的
I found it on short notice.
看起來也是
That's what it looks like.
我站在客廳當中...
So, I was standing in the middle of the living room,
浴室的門也沒關
and the bathroom door opens.
吉婭 吉婭 吉婭
- 怎么了? - 那是誰?
- Yeah? - Who's that?
誰?
Who?
以后我就經常到紐約
I started making trlps to New York regularLy after that.
她希望我留在那里 她希望我一直留在那里
She wanted me there. She wanted me there all the time.
可我不行 我有丈夫 我有個家
I couldn't, you know, because l had a husband, l had a home.
不 不要紅色的 要黃色的 黃玫瑰
No, not red. Yellow. Yellow roses.
我只會留下...
But l would go...
- 給琳達 - 一陣子呆大大概一個星期左右
- To Linda. - ...and l would stay for maybe a week.
有時會呆兩星期
Sometimes l would stay two.
永遠愛你的 吉婭
Love on ya, Gia.
你給女孩子送花?
You're sending fIowers to a girl?
- 這是給你的 小姐 - 好的 謝謝
- Here, lady. - Hi. Got it. Thanks.
見鬼 又是一份黃玫瑰?
Christ, another one?
- 誰死了? - 這不關你的事
- Who died? - None of your business.
你是不是背著我跟個種花的好上了?
Are you fucking a florist behind my back?
是啊 一個穿飛靴的有錢人
Yeah. Gold FTD guy with the winged shoes.
嗨
Hi.
我給你打電話有几個星期了
I've been calling you for weeks.
你好 吉婭
Hi, Gia.
- 這是我男朋友比利 - 你好 我有點醉了
- This is my boyfriend, Billy. - Hi. I'm wrecked.
- 一起進來嗎? - 我想還是算了吧
- Do you wanna come in? - I don't think that's a very good idea.
為什么不?
Why not?
你真的很漂亮
You are really beautiful.
你是個模特 對吧?
You're a model, aren't you?
為什么這么說?我看上去很蠢?
Why? Do I look stupid?
- 我明天還要上班來吧 - 時間還早呢
- I have to work tomorrow. - Come on, it's early.
也許 也許我會可以開個派對
Maybe... Maybe we could party.
你是我見過的最美麗的女人
You are the most beautiful woman that I have ever seen.
跟我來
Come with me.
不
I can't.
好 以后見
Fine, see you around.
那到底是怎么回事?
What the fuck was that?
她就是那個種花的
Behold the florist.
不不不
No, no, no!
我不能再呆了！
I cannot stay!
我還會回來的但現在我必須要走了
Look, I'll come back, but I have to go home now, Gia.
- 我會回來的 - 不不不
- But I'll come back. - No, no, no.
你什么時候需要我就打電話給我
If you need me, you just call me.
我需要你 我現在就需要你
I need you. I need you now.
- 你現在不能走！- 吉婭 吉婭
- You have to be here now! - Gia. Gia. Gia.
我現在就需要你！我需要你 媽媽！
When I need you, I need you now! I need you, Mom !
聽我說你已經是個大姑娘了 對嗎?
Listen to me. You are a big girl, all Right?
- 別走 別走 - 你得有個大姑娘的樣子
- Please! Please! - You are a big girl, act like a big girl.
你已經是大人了
You've got to, and you are.
就得有個大人樣子
So be my big girl.
現在聽我說
Now listen to me.
聽我說 聽我說
Listen to me. Listen to me.
我必須回家了好 好
I have to go home.
必須
I have to.
好 好
Fine. Fine!
- 好 走吧 - 不 吉婭 等等
- Fine. Get out! - No, Gia. All Right, now, wait.
- 等等 - 滾出去
- Wait! - Get the fuck out!
不 別這樣 吉婭
No, not like this, Gia.
我就要這樣 出去！給我滾出去
Yeah, like this! Get out! There. Get the fuck out!
- 吉婭 天啊 - 出去
- Gia, for God's sake. - Get out!
別這樣 別這樣我就要這樣 給我滾出去！
- Not like this, not like this. - Yeah, like this. Get the fuck out!
- 聽著 - 出去 出去
- Look. - There, get out! Get out!
- 好吧 好 好 - 滾
- All Right. Fine, fine, fine. Fine. - Go, go!
- 好吧 好 - 出去
- All Right, fine. - Get out!
好吧 吉婭
Fine, Gia.
就這樣...
That's it.
就...
That...
她這個星期已經約了16場拍攝了 不過我會想辦法的
She's booked for 16 shoots this week, but I'll see what we can do.
想象一下你要沖出包圍...
And you are erupting forms...
告訴斯卡沃布他可以約她
Tell Scavullo he can have her...
除你之外 周圍都是些過氣的人你要讓他們...
...out of the center of all this tired, old beauty.
感到羞愧
Shaming them.
對不起?誰是過了氣的?
Excuse me? "Tired, old beauty"?
你可以找勒尼 我懂你要吉婭 但是六月之前你沒法約到她
You can have Renee. I know you want Gia, but you can't have Gia. Nothing until June.
別讓那個丑婦站在我前面 明白嗎?
This little wop is not standing in front of me. You got that?
要不那我站到一邊好了 再不我走人
I'm off to the side, or I walk.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
這衣服是不是讓我看起來臀部很肥?
Does this dress make my ass look fat?
你的臀部的確比較肥 寶貝
Your ass is fat, honey.
我可不要立 生她的大屁股后面
And I'm not standing next to her fat ass.
我知道
I know.
生活真的很令人失望
Life is so disappointing.
想一下
Here you are.
你來到這里
You have arrived.
這一刻完全屬于你
You are here. This is your moment.
你有什么?
What do you have?
你有的只是痛苦
You have pain.
當你什么都有的時候...
When you have everything,
你還有什么?
what do you have?
你其實什么都沒有
You have nothing.
看上去什么都是好好的 其實沒一樣是對的
When everything is Right, everything is wrong.
令人失望令人困惑
It's disappointing. It's confusing.
這就是生活你能做些什么?
This is life. What can you do?
大家都離開我了 這讓我很難過
People keep going away from me. That hurts.
工作
Work.
工作 你有這個天賦
Work. You have a gift.
好好地利用它
Use it.
生活很快就會美好起來的
Life... Life will be there later.
當你工作過活過了...
When you've worked, and you've llved,
你就會真正了解你自己 生活就是那么簡單
and you know who you are, life is easy.
工作
Work.
這是我唯一知道的答案
It's the only answer I know.
要不是因為我不會唱歌
I should've been a rock star.
我早就成為搖滾明星了
But I can't sing.
現在工作吧
Work now.
工作以后你就會好過些
You can llve later.
你說那么多就是為了要我去干活
You'd say anything to get that shot. Yeah?
- 是的 - 是的
- Yes. - Yes.
可我說的都是真心話
In this case, I'm saying the truth.
甜心
Sweetheart.
畫面應該是這樣你們都恨吉婭...
Now here's the picture. You girls all hate Gia
因為她比你們當中任何一個都漂亮
because she is so much prettier than the rest of you.
你們是那么地讓人感到無趣而她則充滿了激情
And you're all so Boring. She is so exclting.
如果你們不愛聽就當我沒說好了
If you don't like it, please, vanish from my world.
抱歉她現在沒空
No, I'm sorry, she's not avallable.
我知道 但是不行...
l know, darling. You can't get...
她住進了漂亮的大房子...
And she went to live in a beautiful house
大家都喜歡她 她非常地高興
and all the people loved her, and she was very, very happy.
不 她去羅馬了 她正在米蘭拍攝...
No, she's on her way to Rome then. She's shooting Versace in MIlan
然后是去巴黎
and Yves Saint Laurent in Paris.
在巴黎是她的自由之地
Perry has her for the only runway show she's doing.
但是村里的人都很窮...
But the people in the village were very poor,
他們會在她熟睡的時候爬進她的屋子...
and every night, they crept into the house where the girl slept
割下她的金頭發...然后拿去賣錢
and they cut off a piece of her golden hair and they sold it for money.
“他永遠不會注意到的” 他們說
"She'll never even notice," they said.
也因此 她的金發一天天地少去
And so, all the gold was gone from her head.
這是一個真實的灰姑娘式的故事
It's a real cinderella story.
- 叫他快點 - 我的機票哪去了?
- Tell him to hurry. Where's my tickets? - You are wired.
給 試試這個
Here. Try some of this.
這是什么?
What? What is it?
你試了就知道了
The answer to all your prayers.
你唯一要記住的就是：那不是你
The only thing you have to remember is that it's not about you.
他們看到的不是真正的你
lt's not about you. lt's not you that they're looking at.
那不是你
It's not about you.
我現在是金牌模特我知道這點
I'm on top of that. I understand that.
寶貝 這很好 很高興你能那么說
Honey, that's good. I'm so glad about that.
如果你認為你塑造的人物就是你自己的話那你就慘了 知道嗎?
Because if you let it be about you, then you're screwed, you know.
所以你得暫時離開一段時間...
So, you have to stay separate from what's happening
去個什么地方
and you have to be somewhere else.
但我不知道該去哪兒你說去那兒好?
But I don't know where that somewhere else is, you know?
或者該做什么?
Or how to do that.
寶貝 你現在想做什么都行
Honey, you can do whatever you want now.
是嗎?那我到底想要什么呢?
Yeah? What is it I want?
我想要什么呢?
What do I want?
我會成為國王而你則是王后
I will be king, and you will be queen.
我不認為女人就一定是個真正意義上的女人...除非是個金發的 你懂的
I don't think a woman is really a woman unless she's a bIonde, you know.
反響很熱烈啊我從未遇到過這種情況
Response is so enormous. I've never seen anything like it.
好快啊 不是嗎?
And so fast, huh?
這個月有成上百萬的人想為你拍攝
About a million people want to shoot you this month.
我們要以你的名字來命名整個電話線路：吉婭
We're going to name a whole phone line after you. Gia.
我想學攝影
I could Iearn photography.
這應該是我想要做的
That could be something to want. I could...
我可以為孩子拍照
I could photograph chlldren.
我會有我自己的孩子
I could have my own chlldren.
我會送給他們黃玫瑰
I would give them yellow roses.
如果他們太吵了我會帶他們去一個能夠讓他們安靜的地方
And if they got too Ioud, I would just put them someplace quiet.
我會把他們放到烤箱里
I'd put them in the oven.
我會每天給他們一個吻
And I would kiss them every day
并告訴他們‘’你不必出名...
and tell them, "You don't have to be anybody,"
因為我知道 所謂名人其實什么都不是 ' '
because I would know that being somebody doesn't make you anybody anyway.
你對我來說永遠是最重要的
You will always be somebody to me.
永遠是最重要的
在財政方面 威廉敏娜庫伯
And on the financlal front, with the sudden illness of wilhelmina Cooper,
因病前往曼哈頓就醫...
who's still hospitalized in Manhattan,
她現在一切都好 你知道他們還要對她做些檢查
She's doing all Right. You know, they're running some more tests.
也許再過一兩天我們就能知道結果了
Maybe in a day or two, then we'll know something.
你得幫幫我我現在壓力很大
Come on, you gotta heIp me here. I'm under a Iot of pressure.
我沒法給你確切答案
I can't give you any answers.
吉婭
Gia,
我最近一直在考慮關于你的事情
I've been thinking a Iot about you lateLy.
真是太糟糕了 太糟糕了
It's terrible, terrible, isn't it?
我是邁克曼斯菲爾德 新的拉戈代理
Mike MansfieId, starting up the new Largo Agency.
你想一想現在打算怎么辦?
What do you think you're gonna do now?
你這話是什么意思?
What do you mean?
嗯 你是個特別的姑娘
Well, you're a special girl
有著特別問題...
with special problems.
我想你應該得到特別的關注
I think you need special attention.
你可以去福特
You could go to Ford
雖然那兒與上層集團一樣是個鬼地方
and there's always that asshoIe over at Ellte.
但我想你應該考慮一下到我們這邊來
But I think you should put some serious thought into coming with me.
為什么?我為什么要離開維利 ?
Why? Why would I leave Wili?
你應該開始為你自己考慮 你應該堅強
You have to start thinking about yourself. You have to be tough.
這是生意...在這生意當中
This is a business, and in this business
你不可能被一個死人來代表
you can't be represented by a dead woman.
對不起
Excuse me.
有空能不能給我打個電話?
Why don't you give me a call?
是的 我知道這很困難
Yes, darling, I know it's so inconvenient.
把電話本拿來
Get me a copy of the call sheet,
告訴弗雷迪我要與他談談
and tell Freddie I wanted to speak to him 10 minutes ago.
- 好的 我知道了- 吉婭 親愛的 吻我一下
- Done. I'll take care of it. - Gia, darling, kiss me.
是的 我必須去
Yes I have to go too.
- 美好的旅程 - 告訴守點規矩
- Have a wonderful trip. - Tell Christian to behave himself.
再見 親愛的
clao darling.
- 我已經筋疲力盡了 - 我也是
- I'm exhausted. - Me, too.
過來 過來
Come here, come here, come here.
我以為你是病了
I thought you were sick.
我是病了 親愛的我累極了...
I am sick, darling, sick and tired,
但這并不要緊
but it's not serious.
- 我也累極了 - 你?
- I'm tired, too. - You?
對 是的
Yeah. Yeah.
我想我要休息一陣子 你知道我需要時間考慮
I think I wanna stop for a whlle. You know, I need some time to think.
可以 但不是現在 親愛的
Yes, but not now, darling.
以后會有時間給你休息的
PIenty of time to rest when you're in the ground.
現在...
You have...
整個世界都在...
the whole world...
你的掌握之中
at your fingertips.
你一定要挺住抓住機遇
You have to be strong. Seize the moment.
因為如果你不這樣...
Because if you don't,
其她姑娘就會等待機會
there's always another girl waiting Right behind you
把你取而代之...
breathing over your shoulder.
來吧
Come on.
我知道 我知道這很辛苦
I know. I know it's hard.
但我們能做到的......
We can do it.
我們在一起
You and I together.
她看上去真的死了 是嗎?
She really looked dead, didn't she?
死后最令人寬慰的就是沒人關心你看上去怎么樣
The great thing about the afterlife is nobody cares how you look.
就象一個普通平常的女孩子
I can hardly wait.
太有錢了 太瘦了
Too rich and too thin.
- 想到她會得那病 - 你別傳出去
- I had no idea she was that sick. - You can never really tell with Germans.
老天啊！
God !
很好 那樣美極了 太好了 酷
Great. That's beautiful. Okay, really nice. cool.
能不能露多點眼白出來?
Right. Can you roll your eyes back a little so we can see the white under them?
- 我們來張切腹自殺式的照片 - 那是什么?
- We're going for the seppuku look. - What is that?
日本人 不好意思 就是說你要呈半死狀
Japanese. Sorry, it means that you're half dead.
- 我已經是了 - 我知道 太棒了
- I'm there. - I know, it's great.
你做得太好了
You, you are doing so, so good.
真的 你看上去棒極了
Really, you look super.
噢 天啊你是不是想吐啊?
Oh, my God. Did you almost just throw up?
我很不舒服
Look, I'm really sick.
能不能幫我到市中心跑一趟?
Can you go make a run downtown for me, please?
別吐在這衣服上
You're not gonna throw up on this dress, are you?
我真的很不舒服 你去市中心......
Just... I'm sick. Go downtown. All Right?
好嗎?那里有個賣煙的地方 你找“衛星”或者“紈  子弟”
There's a taco place, and you ask for Satellite or rich Boy.
好嗎?好嗎?
Okay? Yeah?
- 毒癮犯了 是嗎? - 是的 對不起
- Chasing the dragon, are you? - Yeah, I'm sorry.
效果很好 無神的眼睛
No, it works, it works. A little death around the eyes.
好太妙了好 太好了 好
Okay, great. Fabulous. Great. Good.
真的太棒了沒話說了
That's really great. That's great.
很好 到摩托右邊很好 壞女孩 壞女孩
Fantastic. Right by the bike. Good. Bad girl, bad girl.
好
Good.
對 就這樣 太好了
Yeah, that's it. Great.
好 很有創意
Good. Fantastic.
- 她失去理智了吧? - 徹麗爾能做到那樣嗎?
- She's out of her fucking mind ! - Could Cheryl Tiegs do this?
我想不能
I don't think so.
走
Go.
嘿 等等！嘿 你上哪兒去?
Hey, wait! Hey, where you going? Hey!
- “衛星”在哪兒?他在這兒嗎? - 在
- Hey, where's Satellite? Is he here? - Yeah.
過來
Come here.
媽的
Fuck.
嘿 你這個裱子
Hey, you bitch.
“衛星”在哪兒?
Where's Satellite?
Where is Satellite?
我病了 媽的 癮君子 他在哪里?
I am sick, fucking junkies. I'm sick! Where is he?
他在外面交易
He's making a dellvery.
- 你們誰有貨啊? - 我注射的這個要不要?
- Is anybody holding anything? Please! - I'll give you my shot.
我不打針的 你有其它的嗎?沒有
I don't shoot. Do you have anything else, dry?
沒有 只有這個
No, man. All I got is in here.
我不要打針
I can't.
- 那好 如果你不要打針的話就算了啊 - 等等
- Okay, if you don't want it... - Wait.
幫我打一針吧你幫我打好嗎?
I want it. You do me. Will you do it?
好
Yeah.
好 我幫你打
Yeah, I'll do you.
會痛嗎?
Is this gonna hurt?
不痛
No pain.
謝謝
Thank you.
別怕 寶貝
Don't be scared, baby.
我會帶你回家的
I'll take you home.
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
哦 上帝
Oh, my God.
我一直在想你
I was thinking about you.
你沒事吧?
Are you okay?
你男朋友在這兒嗎?
Is your boyfriend here?
我已經沒有男朋友了
I don't have a boyfriend anymore.
我全身上下臟極了
I'm all dirty.
我對人們濫用毒品...
I was afraid of the drugs.
很是擔心
The way people used them.
我跟她說過 我是說 她應該知道毒品的危害
I told her that. I mean, she knew that.
我對很多事情都很擔憂
I was afraid of a Iot of things.
她保証過不再吸毒了...
But she promised,
我也相信了她
and l believed her.
我相信我們能夠做到
And l believed we could make things work.
我相信 因為我們都竭盡所能地要做到
l believed because we both wanted it so much that we could.
我們應該可以的
we could...
我們也的確做到了 是的 我們做到了
And we did. we did. we did make it work.
你要回家來?
You're coming home?
你是真的要回家嗎?
You're coming home? Just out of the bIue you're coming home?
就象你現在說的那樣?
Just like that you call me?
真拿你沒辦法
You are a piece of work, you are.
費城?
Philadelphia?
那條母狗現在在費城?
The bitch is in Philadelphia?
做她的經紀人真的是在自殺......
I'm kllling myself trying to keep this agency allve,
太難了...
which is not easy,
我妻子死后 我只得到公司的一半
since my wife with her dying breath screwed me out of 50% of the company.
死女人
Fucking women.
你現在告訴我這個小...
And now you tell me this little
不管她是什么 突然不見了
whateverjust disappears.
我希望她死在費城
I hope she fucking dies in Philadelphia.
這個療程要花21天
It's a 21-day program.
你要每天到這里來吃藥
It's your responslbllity to come in every day and take the methadone.
好的喝口水
All Right. Drink the water.
不用了
That's all Right.
還是喝點水比較好點
I need you to drink the water.
在這里簽字
And slgn next to the line.
好了
Okay.
德韋恩金
Dwayne King.
這是你的 先生 這是剛出爐的
There you are, Mr. Doodiekins. Fresh from the oven.
謝謝你 太太
Thank you, Mrs. Doodiekins.
我能做到 你知道嗎?我可以成為一個家庭主婦
I could do this, you know that? I could be a fucking housewife.
我很高興我能做到
I'd be very happy.
所以 我下廚
So, I cooked.
番茄醬
Ketchup.
晚餐好了
Dinner's ready.
晚餐端上來了
Dinner is served.
這個公寓真的很消沉啊
It's very depressing, this apartment.
好了 好了 閉嘴 媽媽
All Right, all Right. "Shut up, Mom."
琳達今晚是不是要過來...她還住在紐約嗎?
So, is Linda coming back tonight or is she staying in New York?
我不知道如果她工作的晚了 她會留下
I don't know. If she works late, she's gonna stay.
我討厭這戒毒藥它對你的背部產生影響了
I hate what this methadone is doing to your shoulders.
你的背原來是那來直 那么漂亮
They used to stand up so straight, so beautiful.
挺起來
Come on.
你還要注意一下自己的休重
And you have to watch your weight, too.
如果你打算回去工作的話你要好好注意一下自己的外表
You want to look good for when you go back to work.
- 我不會回去工作了 - 好吧
- I'm not going back to work. - Okay.
- 我不能 - 好吧
- I can't. - All Right.
你明白嗎?
Do you understand that?
你的事由你決定 你是知道的
That's how you feel now.
等著瞧吧
But just wait. You'll see.
嗨 這是琳達我現在不在 請留言
Hi, this is Linda. I'm not here. Leave a message.
嗨 是我 我打了一個晚上的電話了你在哪兒?
Hi, Doo- doo. lt's me. I've been calling all night. where are you?
- 琳達 - 喂
- Linda? - Hello?
- 你是誰? - 我是比利 你是哪位?
- Who's this? - This is Billy. Who's this?
吉婭
Gia?
Gia.
媽的！真他媽的... 吉婭 !
Damn it! God damn it, Gia!
天啊 她闖進了我家門 她偷了些錢
Oh, my God, she broke into my house. She stole some money.
她還偷了些珠寶
She stole jewelry.
她去買了毒品...然后她象個瘋子一樣地開車
She bought the drugs and then she took off in the car like a crazy person.
太令人難以置信了
It was unbelievable.
她拿了我的結婚戒指！
She took my wedding ring!
請靠邊停下
Stop the vehicle and pull over.
關于謊言
And the lies.
你知道那個老笑話 你怎么能分辨一個癮君子是不是在撒謊?
You know that old joke, how can you tell when a junkie is lying?
她撒謊了
Her llps are moving.
這一點都不好玩
It's not funny.
從車里出來
Step out of the car.
- 你們為什么要追我?你們瘋了嗎? - 小姐......
- Why are you chasing me? Are you crazy? - Lady.
我要去紐約 而你們卻在他媽的追我?
I'm trying to get to New York, and you're fucking chasing me?
- 好了 小姐 冷靜點 - 你們這是怎么了?
- All Right, ma'am. CaIm down. - What is wrong with you, huh? God !
- 小姐? - 什么?
- Ma'am? - What?
為什么不滾遠點?天啊！
What the... Just back off, okay? God !
- 小姐? - 我必須走了
- Ma'am? - I have to go.
嘿
Hey.
小姐 嘿
Ma'am? Hey!
毫無理由的被逮捕 這就是原因
Get fucking arrested for nothing, that's why.
超速行駛 還拒捕
These are serious charges. Reckless driving.
- 你知道后果有多嚴重嗎?- 他媽的 這不是我的錯！
- This is reslsting arrest. - God damn it! It's not my fault!
也不是我的錯！
It was not my fault either!
他正在我的公寓里收拾他的東西！
He was there getting some stuff out of my apartment!
當時我跟本就不在那里！我正在來這里的路上！
I wasn't even there! I was on my way back here!
謝天謝地 不然你現在還在監獄里
Thank God, because otherwise, you'd still be in jall.
我要回去工作
I have to go back to work.
我知道你要說什么可我需要錢
I know what you're gonna say, but I need the money.
別這樣！
Stop it! Stop it.
有了錢我才能與你在一起我不能再象現在這樣
I need the money so I can be with you, because I cannot llve like this.
我不能現這樣生活了
I cannot llve like this, okay? I can't llve like this.
我也不能沒有你
And I can't llve without you.
你現在想來拉戈了
You want to come to Largo now?
是不是因為別人都不敢與你簽約?
Is that because everyone else is afraid of slgning you?
不 我還沒有與其他人談過
No, I haven't asked anyone else.
那為什么先找我?
Then why me?
因為你是個貪婪的雜種...
Because you're a greedy fuck
你給我的錢應該比別人要多
and you'll get me more money than anyone else.
這倒是事實
That's the truth.
好吧 實話對你說
So, Let me be truthful with you.
大家都知道毒品的事 你太不小心了
Everyone's aware of the drug problem. You weren't very discreet.
我現在不吸毒了...
Well, I'm clean now,
我想要工作
and I want to work.
讓我看看你的手臂
Let me see your arms.
你要的不是我的手臂你要的是我的臉...
It's not my arms you want. It's my face,
還有我的乳房
and my tits.
這兩樣都沒事
And they're fine.
我們正打算為模特拍電視
We're doing a teIevislon piece on models.
我要你也在其中
I want you to be in it.
我希望你能比你以前
I want you to look more beautiful
任何時候都要漂亮
than you have ever looked.
我要你告訴這個世界...
And I want you to tell the world
以前你受毒品的困擾而現在你已經戒了
that you once had a drug problem and now you don't.
現在你是個好姑娘了
Now you're a good little girl.
如果你能做到的話...
If you do that,
我們就成交
we have a deaI.
好的
Okay.
很好
Good.
- 我做不到 - 你能的
- I can't do this. - Yes, you can.
我是個模特 我不能說話
I'm a model. I don't talk.
我不應該說話我只要看上去漂亮就行了
I'm not supposed to talk. I'm supposed to just look beautiful.
你是很美
You are beautiful.
那都是你的功勞
You make me beautiful.
你好
Hello.
好了嗎
Okay. We're all set.
我們都准備好了 要拍你整個化妝過程...
I'm gonna tape you getting made up. Kind of a before- and- after thing.
- 可以 - 還要提一些問題...
- Great. - We've aIso got some interviews
關于你的朋友 家庭 你母親等等...
set up with your friends, your family, your mother.
我母親也要上電視?
You're gonna put my mother on tape?
- 是的 很有可能 - 那樣會更有意思
- Yes, most definitely. - well, that should be interesting.
- 准備好了嗎? - 是的
- You ready? - Yeah.
那太好了
Good.
- 我要上一下廁所 - 當然可以
- I just have to go to the bathroom. - Sure.
你們為什么不到那邊去?
Why don't you guys come over here?
我也這么想 我思考問題很直接
This is what I want. I want the questions to be short and qulck.
你是如何開始接觸模特這一行的?
And how did things first start for you in modeling?
這離不開大家的功勞
I started working with very good people.
是他們使我很快成名 你知道嗎?
A Iot of them. Very fast, you know?
我并非天生就是一個模特
I didn't bulld into being a model.
我只是有那么一點天份
I just sort of became one.
那是如何影響你的?
How has that affected you?
當你還很年青的時候你永遠不會知道
When you're young, you don't always know.
要區分什么是真的 什么不是真的
It's hard to make out the difference
真的是很難...
between what's real and what is not real.
從某一點來說...你是不是因此染上了毒癮
At one point, you kind of got into the drug scene, didn't you?
是的 你可這么說
Yes, yes, you could say that I did.
但你現在不再需要它了 是嗎?
But you're free of it now, aren't you?
當然 我已經完全戒毒了
Yes. DefiniteLy, I'm free of it.
如果我沒戒的話就不可能在這里與你們見面了
I wouldn't be here Right now talking to all of you if I wasn't.
你對自己取得的成就是否感到高興?
Are you happy with your success?
我...
I...
是的 是
Yes. Yeah.
- 當然 - 你好象不是很確定的樣了?
- l am. - You hesltated.
我只是要好好考慮一下這個問題 是的 我當然很高興
I just wanted to think about it. But, no, I'm definiteLy happy with it.
好的 謝謝
Good. Thank you.
好 謝謝
Yeah, thank you.
媽的 媽的怎么回事?
Fuck! What the fuck?
我喜歡踢蜘蛛俠的屁股！
I, like, kick Spider- Man's ass!
對不起別說對不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我只是想讓你笑一笑
I just wanted to make you smlie.
好了
Okay.
好了 我這就走 最后一次
Okay, I'm going. Last chance.
我從前門走
I'm leaving, through the front door.
真受不了你
I can't do this.
別這么說 只要說聲明天見就好了
Don't say that. Just say you'll see me tomorrow.
- 不 你明天不會見到我的 - 不要這么說！
- No, you won't. You won't see me tomorrow. - Don't say that!
不要這么說！
Don't say that.
我們說好的 我們有約定的
We had a deaI. We made a bargain.
我愛你不
I Love you.
你并不愛我
No, you don't.
好 我不愛你 不愛你
All Right, I don't. I don't. I don't.
你是什么人啊?是他媽的警察嗎?
What are you, huh? You some kind of fucking pollceman?
你要審判我嗎?我只吸了一點兒
You going to judge me? I did one fucking line.
就一點
One line.
那有什么大不了的?
What is the big deaI?
那昨天吸了沒有呢?前天呢?
What about yesterday? What about the day before?
沒有
Nothing.
我沒吸 我保証
I did nothing. I promise.
請不要離開我
Please, don't leave me.
我不相信你了
I don't belive you.
你不信我是因為你不愿意信我 是嗎?
You don't belive me because you don't want to belive me, do you?
因為你不在乎我！因為你只是想說...
Because you don't care! Because you just wanted to say,
”我只是一個模特！"
"I'm fucking a model !" Huh? "I'm fucking a model !"
你根本就不關心我 對嗎?
You don't care about me at all, do you?
是嗎?告訴我你不在乎我 說 '’我不在乎！' '
Do you? Tell me you don't care! Say, "I don't care! I don't care!"
我很抱歉
Please. I'm sorry.
我是那么需要你 讓我這樣做
I need you so much. Don't make me do this.
我不能讓你做任何事情
I don't make you do anything.
我希望我能夠
I wish I could.
你可以的 你可以的
You could. You could. You could.
你可以照顧我的
You could take care of me.
- 有30美元嗎? - 沒有
- Do you have $30? - No.
我一點錢都沒有
I don't have any money.
我不知道為什么 我從來都沒有錢
I don't know why. I never have it.
我從來就沒有過一點錢
I never have any money.
在我的絲襪里
In my sock.
- 你就是為了它什么事都做得出來不 - 不是的
- This is what makes you do everything. - No, it doesn't.
不是我 也不是你 是這玩意兒
Yeah. It's not me. It's not you. It's this.
它控制了你
This shit holds you.
- 你自己選吧 - 別這樣
- You choose. - Come on.
要它還是要我
Yeah, this or me.
我要你的手指
Your finger.
你的膝蓋
Your knees.
你的皮膚
Your skin.
你的腳趾頭
Your toes.
我愛你
I Love you.
吉婭
Gia!
她變了
Change.
她的時代過去了
She is over.
現在只是時間問題
It's just a question of time now.
嘿 醒醒
Hey, come on.
- 嗨 - 給你
- Hi. - Yes, you are.
你把這個掉了 寶貝
You dropped this, honey.
還想繼續來完成這場糟糕的時裝秀嗎?
You want to come on and finish this fiasco?
不
No.
你看上去很漂亮
You look so pretty.
是
Yeah.
謝謝
Thanks.
我愛你
I love you.
我知道你愛所有的人
I know. You love everybody.
吉婭 聽著我很想給你一份工作的
Gia, listen to me. l am trying to get you work.
但現在是春季發布會
But it's all spring stuff now.
大家要看的是美麗健康的人
Everybody wants the bIondes with the suntans and the sundresses.
很抱歉 從你身上看不出一點春天的朝氣
I'm sorry. No, your look is not spring.
你看上去更像是個糟糕的冬天 沒有要看的
Your look is more like nuclear fucking winter, and nobody wants it.
把電話挂了
Hang up the phone.
我好緊張
I am so tense.
羅恩 你能不能他媽的用力點
Ron, can you use some of those fucking muscles?
我好緊張
I'm so tense.
當她吻我的時候我感覺就得春風拂面一樣
"When she kisses me, I feel all four winds bIow at my face.
當她不再愛你時你能怎么做?
"But what do you do with a woman who has no love for you?
她已經對我失去興趣了...
"She is my lost captive
現在也沒有任何謊言‘'
"and no longer lies along my legs."
這是我為你寫的
l wrote that for you.
- 為什么他們還讓她露面? - 因為是我要求的
- Why did they send her out? - Because I asked for her.
- 行了吧? - 好的
- All Right? - All Right.
當她們沒有利用價值了
We use them up,
就會被扔到一邊...
throw them away.
不
No.
- 我的刀呢? - 我的刀怎么不見了
- Where's my knife? - I haven't seen it.
誰拿了我刀?
Who took my fucking knife?
我看上去是不是象個他媽的恐怖分子?很好笑嗎?
Who do I look like, a fucking terrorist? Is this funny?
- 你們這些混蛋是怎么了? - 吉婭
- What the fuck is wrong with you people? - Gia.
離我遠點！
Get the fuck away from me!
滾！我的刀呢?
Get away! Where's my knife?
在這兒
Here it is. Here it is.
你知道 你不能這么做
You know, you can't do that.
當別人需要刀子的時候 你不能把它拿走！
You can't take somebody's knife when they need it!
你說得對 好了
It's all Right. It's fine.
- 看看她手臂的疤痕 - 現在好了
- Look at the tracks on her arms. - Okay, now.
還有她手里的那把東西
And that awful thing on her hand.
- 真是可怕 - 好了
- It looks like a voIcano. - All Right.
把你的手臂疊起來
Try... Try folding your arms.
我是說放在你背后
Put them in back of you.
很好 做得不錯
Well, you've almost got it.
現在 把手放在臀部下面
Now, try sltting on your hands.
對 就這樣
Yes, yes.
你看上好極了
You look wonderful.
很美
Beautiful.
- 弗朗西斯科? - 什么事 甜心?
- Francesco? - Yes, sweetheart?
謝謝
Thank you.
吉婭 這就是生活 不是天堂
Gia, this is life, not heaven.
你不用強求事事完美
You don't have to be perfect.
看著我 眼睛在哪里? 嘴巴在那里?
Look at me. Where are those eyes? Where's the mouth?
什么?你不會吧！
What? You're not!
真的?你在飛機上?
TruLy? You're on an airplane?
- 是 - 噢 天哪 聽我說
- Yeah. - Oh, my God ! Listen to me!
我真是太興奮了 太高興了！
I'm so exclted ! I'm yelling !
我高興得要叫出聲了
I don't have to yell, do I?
- 你不用那樣啊 - 亨利
- No, you don't have to yell. - Henry!
- 媽媽 不要與亨利說話 - 他到哪兒去了?別挂
- Mom, I don't want to talk to Henry. - Where is he? Hold on.
你在哪兒?我是說 飛機在哪兒了?
Henry. Where are you? Where are you? I mean, where is the airplane?
我以前從未跟在飛機上的人打過電話
I've never talked to anybody on an airplane before.
過了巴黎... 我想現在快到莫尼黑了
I was in Paris and I think I'm going to Munich.
我不知道
I don't know.
我感覺不是很好
I don't feel so good.
寶貝 你一定是累了?
Well, honey, you're probabLy just tired, you know?
是的...我還有點冷
Yeah, and I'm cold.
你知道...
You know,
我正在想是否要回到家里住 你說呢?
I was thinking about coming home again. What do you think?
寶貝 我覺得這樣不太好
Honey, I don't think so.
你知道?
You know?
- 對 - 我是說 自從你上次離開
- Yeah. - I mean, you know, after the last time.
是 我知道 當然
Yeah, I know. Of course.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
沒什么
Yeah.
我還是回家吧
I better go.
好了 好了
All Right. Okay. All Right.
聽我說 你要好好照顧好你自己
Listen to me. Now, you take care of yourself.
好嗎?給我打電話
Okay? Okay. You call me.
- 好 - 好嗎?我愛你
- Okay. - Okay? Because I love you.
- 再見 - 再見
- Bye. - Bye- bye. Bye- bye.
每個模特都會有光輝的一刻
Every model has a moment,
我是指那個模特...
I mean, the ones who make it at all,
但否將那一刻留芳于世
and whether or not they can parlay that moment
就看運氣了...這就是在賭博 不是嗎?
into some kind of a career, well, that's the gamble, isn't it?
因為那一刻是那么地短暫
'Cause the moment is a very short time.
它轉瞬即逝就好象這些女孩
It's here and then it's gone, just like most of these girls.
她們就在這兒...但很快就不見了
They're here and then they're gone.
當她回到紐約時...我正在費城
when she came back to New York, I was in Philadelphia.
我聽說了一些事情
And l heard some things.
很多事情
A lot of things.
我就坐火車去看她
So l took the train up to see her.
我的錢不見了
I can't find my money.
- 什么? - 我有600美元的 可我找不到了
- What? - I had $600, and I can't find it.
發生什么事了?
What's going on?
我的錢不見了！
I can't find my money!
你這是怎么了?
What's wrong with you?
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
- 你有錢嗎? - 不 我沒錢
- Do you have any money? - No, I don't have any money.
想跟我做愛嗎?
You want to fuck me?
吉婭
Gia.
你給我錢 我就讓你干
You give me money, I'll let you fuck me.
- 到我這里來 - 什么?
- Come here. - What?
不
No.
你做什么?
No, get off! What? No.
- 我可以抱著你嗎? - 放開我！
- Can I please hold you? - Get off! Get off!
- 別再吸毒了 - 走開
- No drugs. - Get off!
放開我！
Get off of me!
- 冷靜點 - 好
- CaIm down. - Okay.
好
Okay.
- 你有醫療保險嗎? - 沒有
- Okay, do you have any medicaI insurance? - No.
- 那你要付現金? - 不 我沒錢
- Can you pay cash for this? - No, I don't have any money.
愚蠢的問題
Stupid question.
那好 你必須申請破產
All Right. You'll have to declare yourself indigent.
你明白嗎?
Do you understand that?
等一下
wait a minute.
要我因為你長得漂亮因為你無所事事就同情你?
what, am I supposed to feel sorry for you because you're beautiful?
因為你每分鐘賺一萬塊而無所事事?
Because you made 10,000 a minute doing fucking nothing?
這不可能 沒人能夠這樣要求我
"It was so hard, so terrible. They treated me so bad."
聽著 你本來生活得不錯...但你不要了
Listen, girl. You had a free ride and you fucking blew it.
而我...
And me?
我來自俄亥俄...
I'm some kid from Ohio,
讀著時尚雜志 看著你的照片 心里想...
reading fashion magazines, looking at your picture and thinking,
如果我是那樣的話...
"I'm supposed to look like that,"
我會瘋了的因為我不
and going fucking crazy because I don't.
因為沒人對我說那是假的
Because nobody told me it was a lle.
因為雜志上沒有注明...
Because the magazine doesn't come with a label that says,
注意 這是假的沒人會是那樣的
"Caution. This is a lle. Nobody looks like this."
即使是你
Not even you.
他們叫我去我就去了 我也努力過
well, they asked me to go to the sesslons, so I did. l trled.
我真是瘋了 我瘋了
I just got so mad. I got so mad.
我對他們說 看 我不是吸毒的
I said to them, "Look, I'm not the drug addict here.
我不是那種隨便讓你們支來支去的人我說 都過去了 就讓它過去了吧
"I'm not the one that you should be rlpping apart."
為什么你就不能讓它算了呢?
I said, "This is all burled. Why don't you just let it be?"
這就是我對他們說的
That's what I told 'em. Look, I know. I know.
你們想怪罪別人你們想怪罪我
You want to blame somebody. You want to blame me.
好吧 來吧
Okay, go ahead. Knock yourself out.
但你們要記住： 我做過的每一件事我所做的一切都是因為我愛她
But just remember this, everything I did, I did because I loved her.
我相信那就是我的愛...我也祈禱她能得到那份愛
And I belive that it was my love and my prayers that got her through that.
嗨 琳達 我是吉婭
Hi, Linda, it's Gia.
我是來向你道歉的
I'm calling to apologize.
我正在治療中...
I'm in this program
治療的一部分就是...
and it's, like, part of the program that we're supposed to
希望得到那些在我們吸毒時傷害過的人的原諒
ask forgiveness of the people that we hurt when we were drugging.
我就像“和男人干 可以休息一下”
I was like "Well fuck man. That could take the rest of my life."
對不起 這很愚蠢
I'm sorry. This is stupid.
但無論如何 我還是希望得到你的諒解...
Anyway, I'm calling to ask forgiveness
并且要說 我想你 因為
and to say that I miss you, because...
喂?
Hello?
怎么回事?
what is that? Am l done?
我想我說完了我不知道發生了什么事
l think I'm done. l don't know what happened.
喂 是我
Hi. Hi, it's me.
男孩琳達
Boy, Linda.
是的
Yeah.
嗨
Hi.
這下我不知道該說什么了
Well, now I don't know what to say.
沒事 我在聽我一直在聽著
It's okay. I heard you. I heard it all.
真的沒事嗎?
Is that okay?
是的
Yeah.
我不能說了 我要走了 過几天再打電話給你行嗎?
I can't talk Right now. I have to go. Can I call you in a few days?
這几天我要出去 回來后給你打電話好嗎?
I'm gonna be out in a few days, and then I'm gonna call you, okay?
好的
Okay.
看了這個你就知道她為何總說自己是個模特了
You know how she's always saying she's a model?
哦 天啊
Oh, my sweet Jesus!
這就是她?
Is that her?
很難想象她會在這里疊牛仔服...
God, she's been folding the same pair of jeans for the last five minutes.
還有一件事 你不會想在那地方做事
And that's another thing. You don't want to work in a place like that, Gia.
討厭的地方討厭的人
UgLy, ugLy place. UgLy people.
媽媽 那地方不錯
Mom, listen. This is the good part.
很好
This is good.
一切真的開始好轉了嗎?
Everything's gonna be really good from now on, okay?
好的
Okay.
看看看看你的皮膚
Look at this. Look at your skin.
媽媽
Mom.
什么?那只個小瘡疤 沒事的
What? It's just acne. It's okay. It'll go away.
只是我體內的毒素被逼出來了而已
It's the drugs. They're coming out of my system.
很快就會好的
I'm gonna look really good.
到了聖誕節我一定會很漂亮的
And by Christmas, I'm gonna look great.
我們將會過一個愉快的節日
And we are gonna have the best hoilday ever.
你為什么不到家里來
Why don't you come home, huh?
跟我一起回去好嗎?
Move back in with me. Would you like that?
不
No,
我想一個人
I gotta be alone.
能不能借我點錢買咖啡和牙膏?
But can you Iend me a few bucks for coffee and toothpaste?
哦 說到咖啡！
The coffee!
不好意思 我忘了
I'm sorry. I forgot.
你以前賺的錢本該足夠過你的余生的
You know, with the money you made, you could have llved the rest of your life.
好了 這只是我的建議
Well, that's what happens, I suppose.
- 怎么了? - 我覺得有點頭暈
- What? - I'm just feeling dizzy.
- 怎么了? - 媽媽
- What is it? - Mom.
吉婭
Gia.
你發燒了
Honey... Honey, you're burning up.
- 我覺得耳朵不舒服 - 我的孩子
- Why do my ears hurt? - Baby.
不不不 哦 天啊
No, no, no, no, no. Oh, my God.
你得了肺炎...這個我們可以醫治好
You have pneumonia, which we can treat.
吉婭 聽著
Gia, listen.
但更為嚴重的是使你感染肺炎的原因
There's something more serious going on which caused your infection.
那就是愛滋病
Something they're calling Acqulred Immune Deficlency Syndrome.
- 你也說聽過說吧? - 沒有
- Maybe you heard about it? - No.
我怎么會得那種病的?
How did I get it?
我們剛剛查出來...而你是我遇到的第一個得這種病的女人
Well, we're really just finding things out and you're the first woman I've known about.
通過靜脈注射吸毒的人得這種病機率很高
AIthough, intravenous drug users seem to be an especlally high- risk group.
你可能是由于使用了受污染的注射器引起的
So you probabLy got it from a contaminated needIe.
怎么才能治好?
How do I get rld of it?
他們怎么知道?他們對這種病也是一無所知
But how do they know? They don't know anything about it.
他們知道的 但沒法治療
They know, okay? They just know.
你知道我在想什么嗎?
You know what I think?
我想每件事情都有它發生的理由
I think there's a reason for everything.
我想上天對每個人都有一個安排
And I think that there's a plan for everybody.
我想上帝已經為我做了最好的打算...
And I think that God has a big plan for me.
只是不是在我活著的時候
Just not in this life.
我在萬物之上
I'm on top of everything. I'm super cool.
你現在看上去好多了
You've gotten better.
我不能帶他回家
I can't take her home.
我想 但是亨利怕
I'm trying, but Henry, he's just afraid.
什么?
So what?
布萊爾醫生...
Dr. Blair...
她是你的女兒 你的女兒
This is your daughter. Your daughter.
大家都很害怕我也很怕
So people are scared. I am scared.
他怕這事被人知道了他可能會丟了工作
He's afraid that if people find out, he could lose his job.
好 很好
Fine. Okay, fine. Fine.
那她該上哪兒去?
And where is she going to go?
他要她去住旅館他說錢由他出
He wants her to go to a hoteI. He says that he'll pay for it.
天阿 聽我說
Oh, God, listen to me.
聽我說
Listen to me.
布魯斯醫生 有電話找
Dr. Bruce, telephone, please. Dr. Bruce, telephone, please.
她的父親呢?他不能照顧她嗎?
What about her father? Why can't he take her? Can he take her?
她不想讓他知道
She doesn't want him to know.
我也不想失去我的孩子
I don't want to lose my baby.
- 凱西里恩 - 不 不行
- Kathleen. - No, I can't. I can't.
好吧...你要明白
well, you have to understand.
在那些日子里...
ln those days,
沒有人知道
nobody knew.
大家都很害怕 我也是
People were scared. I was scared.
她自己也一定怕極了
She must have been scared, too.
親愛的琳達 這是我的書的最后一部分
Dear Linda, this is the end of my book.
最后一張 最后一頁
The last page, the last shot.
看到你對我說你好 再見
Seeing you to say hello and goodbye.
看到你填補所有的空白...你的昧道 你的觸摸...
Seeing you to fill up all the empty, and smell and touch,
把我的吻都留在你的臉上
and leave my kisses all over your face.
- 吉婭 - 是我
- Gia. - That's me.
進來吧
Come in. Come in.
來點茶嗎?
Do you want some tea?
看到你我好緊張 咖啡?
I was so nervous about seeing you. Coffee?
不 我馬上就走
No, I can't stay Iong.
為什么?
Why not?
我有個約會
I have an appointment.
工作?
Work?
我再也不用工作了
No. No. No more work for me.
我想我們會有更多時間在一起
I just thought we'd have more time.
我也是這么想的
Yeah, me, too.
只是不是今天
Just not today.
好吧
That's okay.
我們會擁有全世界的時間
We have all the time in the world. We'll take it.
我也這么認為
Yeah, I guess so.
但今天我只想看看你的臉
But today I just wanted to see your face.
我很想念你的面容
I missed your face.
你有什么打算?
What are you going to do?
我不知道 我想...
I don't know. I have some plans.
我可能去讀書 去學些有用的東西
I think I might go to schooI, you know? Learn something useful maybe.
或許安頓下來 要几個孩子 天知道
Maybe even settIe down and have some kids, you know?
這真是...
What the hell?
喔
Wow.
你現在好坦誠啊
How straight are you now?
我是說 你指的是男人嗎?
I mean, are we talking about men?
并不是要有丈夫才能有孩子的
You don't need a husband to have kids.
我說 我的心里只有你一個 你知道嗎?
And besides, you were the one who always had my heart, you know?
是的 這點我想我知道
Yeah, I guess I did know that.
你能為我保存這些東西嗎?
Would you keep these for me?
- 你的童話故事? - 是的 有一些
- Your fairy tales? - Yeah, some. A few.
還有其它一些我自己的涂鴉
Plus all the other crazy shit in my head.
我不想把它們扔了
I don't want to throw it away, but I just don't want it around Right now.
- 你想看就看看吧 - 不 我不看
- You can read it if you want. - No, I won't.
看看吧我要你看的
No, read it. Read it. I want you to, you know?
許可以看出些什么而我從來沒看出來
Maybe you can make some sense out of it. I never could.
- 好的 - 好
- Okay. - Okay.
- 我還會再見到你的 對嗎? - 當然 你想去?
- I'm gonna see you again, aren't I? - Yeah, you want to?
對
Yeah. Yeah.
你知道 我一直在想...
You know, I was thinking about
這個夏天到海邊買棟房子
getting a house at the beach this summer.
- 是嗎? - 是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
我很希望我們可以從那兒開始重新來過
I really thought that it would give us a chance.
我真的非常希望我們能夠重新來過
I would like so much for us to have another chance.
是啊 我也是
Yeah, I'd like that, too.
我要走了
I gotta go.
- 不 等等我要你留下來 - 好
- No, wait. I want you to stay. - Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
你是我的唯一 我的唯一
You were the one. You were the only one.
你是我的奇跡
And you are amazing.
她...
She...
她把錢收集起來
She put together this money.
她當了一些東西... 向父親借了一些...
She pawned some things, borrowed some from her father,
從凱西里恩那里偷7點
stole some from Kathleen.
當時我不知道
I didn't know what she was doing.
我本該知道的...可我不知道
l should have, but I didn't.
可能是思維定式
It may have crossed my mind.
我真的沒想到她會那樣做
l really didn't think she would do that.
真的沒想到
I really didn't.
吉婭 近來怎么樣?
Yo, Gia. How you doing?
- 很好 他在嗎? - 他在后面
- Good. Is he here? - Yeah, yeah, he's in the back.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 你要多少? - 你有多少?
- How much you want, angeI? - As much as you've got.
你要那么多用來做什么?
What are you gonna do with that much stuff?
那是我自己的事
Well, that's my business.
- 你到底有還是沒有? - 你急什么?
- What, are you holding or not? - What's your hurry?
好了 說吧 有還是沒有?
All Right. Come on. Yes, or no?
是的 我有你想要的...這就是你想要的
Yeah, I got what you need, and I got it Right here.
你他媽的做什么啊?
Yo, man, what the fuck are you doing, man?
- 看看聖誕老人給我們帶什么來了? - 我他媽的走了
- Look what Santa claus brought us. - I'm freaking out of here!
你拿錢我也有份
You get the money. I'm gonna get mine.
一切都會好起來的
It's gonna be all right.
凱西里恩
Kathleen
你來這里做什么?
what are you doing here?
我要帶你回家 孩子
I'm gonna take you home, baby.
她不想見任何人...但我還是去了
She wouldn't let anybody see her, but l went anyway.
我只見了她一面
l saw her once.
但我確實見到了
But I did see her.
- 我想她沒認出我來 - 不要超過5分鐘
- l don't think she knew it was me. - No more than five minutes, okay?
我忍不住對自己說天啊 她還只是個孩子
I couldn't help thinking to myself, "My God, she's just a kid."
我很自責 你知道嗎?
I blame myself, you know?
這只是孩子
I mean, these are chlldren.
無論我們的生活多么艱難... 我們都應該照顧好我們的孩子
No matter how screwed up our llves may be we've got to take care of our chlldren.
她自己知道命不長了
She knew she was dying.
她說她要做件事
She said she wanted to do it Right.
她要一架攝影機...
She wanted to get a video camera
她要告訴孩子們關于毒品的事
and do this thing where she talked to kids about drugs.
她想告訴孩子們...
She wanted to tell kids
無論遇到什么誘惑
that you can handle it.
都不要輕易上勾
You can handle anything that comes your way.
但我們沒有拍
But we never got the camera.
你是最漂亮最漂亮的女孩
You do be the prettiest, prettiest girl.
你是的
You do be that.
真的嗎?
Do I?
我真的是最漂亮的嗎?
Do I be the prettiest?
是
Yeah.
不
No.
你能原諒我嗎凱西里恩 ?
Do you forgive me, Kathleen?
哦 親愛的
Oh, honey.
是的
Yeah.
當然
Of course I do.
因為我也原諒了你
Because I forgive you, too.
親愛的
Baby.
這是什么?
What's this?
What is it?
天啊
Oh, my God.
護士?護士
Nurse? Nurse!
- 你去哪兒?媽媽? - 護士?
- Where are you going, Mom? - Nurse!
媽媽?
Mom?
你去哪兒?
Where you going?
她大概是在早上1 0 : 00去世的
She died around 1 0:00 in the morning.
他們試圖把她...
They trled to pick her...
他們試圖把她救活 可她
They trled to pick her up off the bed, and she...
她就這樣離我們而去了
The flesh just fell off her back. It just fell off.
你不會想聽這些的
You don't want to hear about that.
還有什么?
Okay, what else? What else?
就是這個這個就是我要找的
Yeah, this is it. This is what I was looking for.
村里的人說 她不再美麗了
"And the people said, 'Oh, she's not beautiful at all.'
他們把她趕出了那所漂亮的房子...把她扔到了大街上
"And they took her from the beautiful house and they drove her into the street.
她走了...再也不回去了
"And she went away and she never came back.
不久 人們又貪婪了...他們回到那所漂亮的房子...
"And soon, people became hungry again and they went back into the beautiful house
尋找金子可那里再也沒有金子了
"looking for gold, but there was no one there."
他們說她知道 她的確知道她知道所有的事
They say she knew. She really knew. She knew the whole story.
我們為她舉辦了葬禮相信我 這不是一件容易的事
we found an undertaker, and it was hard, believe me,
你知道 因為艾滋病
you know, because of the AIDS.
我不希望人們因為這個而記住她...
I didn't want people to remember her like that
因為我不希望人們用這種眼光來看待她
because I didn't want people to see her like that.
我希望人們能記住她的美... 因為她的確是很美
I wanted them to remember her as beautiful, because that's what she really was.
生命與死亡...
Life and death,
活力與安詳
energy and peace.
如果我今天就死了這一切還是值得了
If I stop today, it was still worth it.
我所犯的最大的錯誤...和我本可能犯但是沒有犯的
Even the terrible mistakes that I have made and would have unmade if I could.
以及痛苦已經將我燃燒 令我恐懼
The pains that have burned me and scarred my soul.
但一切都是值得的...
It was worth it
因為我已體會過了人間的地獄...
for having been allowed to walk where I've walked,
體會過了人間的天堂
which was to hell on Earth, heaven on Earth,
又回到了地獄...又回到了天堂...回到二兩者的距離...經歷它...
back again, into, under, far in between, through it,
感受它...超越它
in it and above.
摘自吉婭瑪瑞卡蘭芝的日記1960一1986